<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Franck Chauvel</title>
    <link>//fchauvel.github.io/categories/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Franck Chauvel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//fchauvel.github.io/categories/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Architecture in Practice, by L. Bass</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/11/08/software-architecture-in-practice-by-l.-bass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/11/08/software-architecture-in-practice-by-l.-bass/</guid>
      <description>Why should you read about Software architecture? Who even cares in these Agile and DevOps times. Should you, for whatever reason, still be interested, this book is a good place to approach software architecture from its theory side.
Here comes a book I had on my reading list for decades: Software Architecture in Practice, by L. Bass, P. Clements, and R. Kazman. I should have read this one when I was a PhD student, but I guess I was too lazy by then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Architecture, by R. Martin</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/11/01/clean-architecture-by-r.-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/11/01/clean-architecture-by-r.-martin/</guid>
      <description>Does software architecture sound like a vague philosophical idea, disconnected from the practicalities of programming? Yes? This might be a good read.
I liked Clean Code and The Clean Coder by R. Martin, I felt tempted to read this other volume about software architecture. While I had been hesitating for some time, reading just enough software architecture by G. Fairbanks revamped my interest, and I took the (tiny) plunge. Besides, I got to try the Amazon Kindle for the first time, and I liked it!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>