<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book-review on Franck Chauvel</title>
    <link>//fchauvel.github.io/categories/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book-review on Franck Chauvel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//fchauvel.github.io/categories/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Data-intensive Applications</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/17/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/17/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid>
      <description>Are you lost in the jungle of (big-)data technologies? Are you wondering how the Flink, Spark, Hive, Pig, Airflow and the likes fit together? Then this is the right book!
I found it as a recommendation on Goodreads.com. I wanted to learn about data technologies as I work more and more on this and I felt it was a good match: It was recent enough (2017), and was available on Google Play within my budget (EUR 12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Software Architecture</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/26/just-enough-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/26/just-enough-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>If just like me, you lost faith in models and model-driven engineering (MDE) a long time ago, this book might help. It shows how to reconcile architecture and modelling with agility and maintaining real software.
Just enough software architecture advocates modelling software until we feel confident enough to proceed with writing code. That is, if some technical risks (availability, maintainability, etc.) are not yet under control, then we should (re-)think how architectural decisions that could help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to win friends and influence people by D. Carnegie</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/11/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-by-d.-carnegie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/11/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-by-d.-carnegie/</guid>
      <description>Are you struggling to convince people, to get them to say yes, this book by D. Carnegie might be for you.
D. Carnegie proposes a catalogue of tips and tricks to better deal with people, including how to make people like you, how to win people to your way of thinking and, how to be a leader. These range from very simple things like smiling, to more skilful techniques such as asking questions instead of arguing (the Socratic method).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life of Benjamin Franklin by M. L. Weems</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/01/the-life-of-benjamin-franklin-by-m.-l.-weems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/01/the-life-of-benjamin-franklin-by-m.-l.-weems/</guid>
      <description>We all know Benjamin Franklin — even I knew his name and inventions. But do you know the person he was, how he lived and who he aimed at?
This one was initially published in 1817 and was digitized the Google Book Search program. The original title is a bit of a mouthful: &amp;ldquo;The Life of Benjamin Franklin, written chiefly by himself, with a collection of his essays, humorous, moral and litterary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I raised myself from failure to success in selling by F. Bettger</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/08/21/how-i-raised-myself-from-failure-to-success-in-selling-by-f.-bettger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 07:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/08/21/how-i-raised-myself-from-failure-to-success-in-selling-by-f.-bettger/</guid>
      <description>If you ever wondered how a baseball player can become a successful saleman, this book is for you?
Franklin L. Bettger (1888 – 1981) explains how he transition from baseball to sales, sucessfully. In this text published in 1947, he gather &amp;ldquo;tatics&amp;rdquo; that helped him eventually succeeed. He covers general ideas that helped him sell more, ways he won confidence, tricks he used to induce other to do business for him, tips on how he approached sales, and finally, how he overcame failures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>