<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Franck Chauvel</title>
    <link>//fchauvel.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Franck Chauvel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//fchauvel.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to take smart notes, by S. Ahrens</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/24/how-to-take-smart-notes-by-s.-ahrens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/24/how-to-take-smart-notes-by-s.-ahrens/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel that you never have any idea or that your ideas are irrelevant or impractial? This book tells how to generate ideas by reading and taking notes!
Yet another book that Goodreads.com recommended. I always felt my notes taking is inadequate: In meetings, I often note only the irrelevant. But this is not about writing meeting minutes. It is about taking generating ideas by taking notes while reading—as the subtitle says.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Data-intensive Applications</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/17/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/10/17/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid>
      <description>Are you lost in the jungle of (big-)data technologies? Are you wondering how the Flink, Spark, Hive, Pig, Airflow and the likes fit together? Then this is the right book!
I found it as a recommendation on Goodreads.com. I wanted to learn about data technologies as I work more and more on this and I felt it was a good match: It was recent enough (2017), and was available on Google Play within my budget (EUR 12).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Software Architecture</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/26/just-enough-software-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/26/just-enough-software-architecture/</guid>
      <description>If just like me, you lost faith in models and model-driven engineering (MDE) a long time ago, this book might help. It shows how to reconcile architecture and modelling with agility and maintaining real software.
Just enough software architecture advocates modelling software until we feel confident enough to proceed with writing code. That is, if some technical risks (availability, maintainability, etc.) are not yet under control, then we should (re-)think how architectural decisions that could help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to win friends and influence people by D. Carnegie</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/11/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-by-d.-carnegie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/11/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-by-d.-carnegie/</guid>
      <description>Are you struggling to convince people, to get them to say yes, this book by D. Carnegie might be for you.
D. Carnegie proposes a catalogue of tips and tricks to better deal with people, including how to make people like you, how to win people to your way of thinking and, how to be a leader. These range from very simple things like smiling, to more skilful techniques such as asking questions instead of arguing (the Socratic method).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life of Benjamin Franklin by M. L. Weems</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/01/the-life-of-benjamin-franklin-by-m.-l.-weems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/09/01/the-life-of-benjamin-franklin-by-m.-l.-weems/</guid>
      <description>We all know Benjamin Franklin — even I knew his name and inventions. But do you know the person he was, how he lived and who he aimed at?
This one was initially published in 1817 and was digitized the Google Book Search program. The original title is a bit of a mouthful: &amp;ldquo;The Life of Benjamin Franklin, written chiefly by himself, with a collection of his essays, humorous, moral and litterary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I raised myself from failure to success in selling by F. Bettger</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/08/21/how-i-raised-myself-from-failure-to-success-in-selling-by-f.-bettger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 07:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/08/21/how-i-raised-myself-from-failure-to-success-in-selling-by-f.-bettger/</guid>
      <description>If you ever wondered how a baseball player can become a successful saleman, this book is for you?
Franklin L. Bettger (1888 – 1981) explains how he transition from baseball to sales, sucessfully. In this text published in 1947, he gather &amp;ldquo;tatics&amp;rdquo; that helped him eventually succeeed. He covers general ideas that helped him sell more, ways he won confidence, tricks he used to induce other to do business for him, tips on how he approached sales, and finally, how he overcame failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Quick-check</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/02/05/introducing-quick-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 15:57:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2020/02/05/introducing-quick-check/</guid>
      <description>I recently released quick-check, a JS library to easily declare data schema and validate and convert data accordinly.
Why Yet Another Library? I did not find anything that fits my need. I ended up writing some boiler-plate code, code to convert object trees (i.e., maps and lists) into home-grown classes, first while working on the CAMP project (Python), and then on my RPP project.
I did find though libraries to convert JSON files into home-grown classes, using annotations for instance, but in my case, I needed to accept both objects trees from multiple syntax files, say TOML and YAML for instance, which I parsed using different libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Emergent Auto-Scaling</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2017/03/10/exploring-emergent-auto-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 12:38:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2017/03/10/exploring-emergent-auto-scaling/</guid>
      <description>I noted that services tend to become smaller and more intelligent. Microservices for instance now encompass various resiliency mechanisms such as active queue management (AQM), auto-scaling or retry/back-off to name only a few. As services are distributed in nature, I am wondering what behaviour will emerge from interactions of such autonomous (micro-)services.
While reading &amp;ldquo;Signals and Boundaries&amp;rdquo; (Holland 2012), I wonder about the simplest model that could lead, for instance, to a feature like auto-scaling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reviews I Wish to Get</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/11/16/the-reviews-i-wish-to-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 14:49:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/11/16/the-reviews-i-wish-to-get/</guid>
      <description>As a researcher, I submit research articles for peer-review. The reviews I get are unfortunately too often deceptive—not only because most are rebuttals. These reviews are of very little use, beyond improving my broken English.
Below are the key points I wish reviewers would discuss. As a matter of fact, I do also consider them when I write reviews. While I am aware of the time it takes to write a detailed review, I am convinced that it does help moving research in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Automatically Deploy on Gandi?</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/08/28/how-to-automatically-deploy-on-gandi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 07:38:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/08/28/how-to-automatically-deploy-on-gandi/</guid>
      <description>I host fchauvel.net (this very website) on Gandi.net. I use Hugo to generate it and I explain below how, each time I update its content, I automatically upload the new website.
Upload to Gandi.net using LFTP Gandi offers several hosting solutions, from which I have chosen simple hosting. Generally, I use rsync or scp to upload all my content in one go, but Gandi restricts access to either SFTP or GIT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting more productive!</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/08/23/getting-more-productive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 15:45:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/2016/08/23/getting-more-productive/</guid>
      <description>I am often disappointed by my daily organisation: I discard many of my projects, and most of them do not live to my expectations. One thing that especially bugs me is to fail making progress on multiple projects at the same time. I am diving into one particular project and, when I emerge two weeks later, every other things have gone bad. This is especially true for development tasks, where I get bogged down, consistently.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>