<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about-me on Franck Chauvel</title>
    <link>//fchauvel.github.io/categories/about-me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about-me on Franck Chauvel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 16:54:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//fchauvel.github.io/categories/about-me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 16:54:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>I like coding and I am lucky enough to get the opportunity to develop open source software as part of my job. I have been involved in development of the tools including:
  CAMP helps you amplify your configuration tests. Given your docker resources, CAMP will run your tests in multiple environments, giving you confidence!
  CloudML helps you deploys your application accross multiple clouds, such as AWS, Azure, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Activities</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 14:53:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests I am a software engineer who ended up doing applied research. My interests therefore revolve about programming and software engineering.
  Complex Adaptive Systems fascinates me, especially distributed ones. I observe that as software systems grow in both in size and complexity, they resemble complex adaptive systems, whose behaviour is difficult to understand, let alone to predict.
  Agile Software Development and the software craftsmanship ideas struck me as obvious once we know them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biography</title>
      <link>//fchauvel.github.io/biography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 13:29:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//fchauvel.github.io/biography/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Franck! I have always been passionate about writing software. While I started as a programmer (BS and MS in Computer Science), my need to learn and explore led me to research more than 15 years ago. My enthusiasm and curiosity turned me into a &amp;ldquo;Swiss knife&amp;rdquo;: Not only do I help design, manage, sell research &amp;amp; innovation projects in Software Engineering, but I also write code! I have joined numerous national and international research projects and occupied various roles (engineer, work package leader, coordinator) and keep enjoying working with ever-changing cutting-edge technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>